Finding Aid for Brian K. Johnson papers, 1974-1992
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Brian K. Johnson papers 1974-1992 1989-1991
Johnson, Brian K.
0.5 linear feet and 1 tube
2010072 Aa 2
Documentation of the environmental issues and legal proceedings associated with the Traxler Landfill in Pinconning, Michigan.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Collection received from Brian Johnson in 2009 (donor no. 10256 ).
Periodic additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Brian K. Johnson of Johnson Consultants, Jackson, Michigan served as a consultant on issues related to the Traxler Landfill.
In 1989, a construction permit was issued by the Michigan Department of Natural Resources to Traxler Landfill Inc., authorizing construction of a new landfill for solid waste disposal on a 100 acre site in Pinconning Township in Bay County Michigan. Both the local community and environmental activists opposed the landfill due to concerns about negative impacts on the surrounding wetlands, groundwater quality, and the proximity to Whitefeather Creek and Saginaw Bay.
The collection includes reports, correspondence, drawings, and newspaper clippings that document the controversy over the Traxler Landfill in Pinconning Township, Michigan.
In addition, there are materials documenting the incorporation of Dumpbusters, a non-profit organization dedicated to prevention of further pollution of natural resources, and active in the controversy surrounding the Traxler Landfill.
Subjects:
Johnson, Brian K.; Landfills--Michigan--Pinconning.; Michigan. Dept. of Natural Resources.; Waste disposal in the ground--Michigan.; Wetlands--Michigan.
- Traxler Landfill file
  - Reports and reference materials, 1989-1991 (Box 1)
  - Construction permits, 1989 and 1991 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence and legal documents, 1984-1992, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Meeting minutes of the Pinconning Township Board, 1984-1991 (scattered) (Box 1)
  - Meeting notes (Box 1)
  - Dumpbusters
    - 501C incorporation, bylaws, and miscellaneous background information, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
    - Billing for consultation, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
    - Database research (Box 1)
  - Michigan Department of Natural Resources newsletters, memos, reports, 1989-1992 (Box 1)
  - Clippings and publicity, 1990-1992 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous photographs (including Traxler construction site), 1990 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (including samples from Gundle Lining Systems Company) (Box 1)
  - Site plan drawings, 1990-1991 (Tube 1)
  - Building blueprints, 1990-1991 (Tube 1)
  - Map of flood plan area in Pinconning quadrangle, 1974 (Tube 1)